# **CHERAN SENGODAN**

**Tech Lead** 

+91 78459-31506

@ cheran15061992@gmail.com

e https://www.linkedin.com/in/cheransengodan-58a162148/

11/90 Madathur, Konganapuram, PErumaipatty PO, Idapadi TK, Salem -

### **SUMMARY**

I am a Tech Lead with extensive experience in software development across various industries. I have successfully led teams in developing innovative applications, specializing in technologies like Laravel, IVR systems, and blockchain integrations. My ongoing dedication to personal and professional growth motivates me to embrace new challenges while contributing positively to my team's success.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### PHP/Laravel Developer

#### EliteCode Technological Solutions PVT LTD

**m** 03/2015 - 02/2018

Coimbatore

Company specializing in technological solutions.

- Started career with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JS and PHP, Laravel framework.
- Developed valuable expertise in quickly mastering new technologies under highpressure conditions

#### Programmer Analyst Software Developer

#### **Srinsoft Technologies PVT LTD**

**=** 03/2018 - 03/2019

Chennai

Focused on software development and application solutions.

- Learned SASS application development.
- Expanded skill set in a new work environment.
- Gained valuable experience working on projects.

#### Senior Software Developer

### Elumina e Learning PVT LTD.

E-learning solutions provider.

- Learned about Docker, microservices, and product development architecture.
- Enhanced understanding of modern development practices and frameworks.

#### Senior Software Developer

# **FORUS Technologies**

Technology solutions across various sectors.

- Managed multiple projects under pressure.
- Improved multitasking skills.

# Software Engineer

# **Pudding app India private limited**

Startup focused on innovative applications.

- Developed POW project at a startup company.
- Enhanced performance optimization.
- Mentored junior team members.

#### Tech Lead

#### **Sensiple Software Solutions**

# 06/2022 - Present ♀ Chennai

Provider of various software solutions.

- Managed two teams simultaneously as a Tech Lead.
- Implemented IVR applications, enhancing customer interaction.
- Led the development of ICO applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

# BE MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

# ARCHANA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY/ANNAUNIVERCITY

### **LANGUAGES**

**English** Proficient

**Tamil** 

Native



#### **SKILLS**

HTML	CSS JA		VASCRIPT		REACT		
EXPRESS	NODE JS		PYTHON		PHP		
CI/CD	LARAVEL		BOOTSRAP		MYSQL		
Docker	MONO	ODB	GCP		Git	Github	
Google Ar	nalytics	RI	EDIS	OPEI	IAI		
REST API KOA J		JS	S JIRA JO		Query		
NERVE FRAMEWORK		RK	GSAP JS		JEN	JENKINS	
GITLAB	AJAX	_ E	BLOCKCH	IAIN	_		
ETHERUM					ONW		

# **PYTHON DJANGO**

# **PROJECTS**

# Crypto Trading Exchange

## 12/2023 - Present

Cryptocurrency trading exchange project.

Architect, programming, & managing a team for Binance API integration & developing web3 wallets.

# Dultmeier

Multi-vendor shopping cart project.

- Developed multiple modules like users, admin, vendor.
- Managed 4 members for this project.

#### Cloudsens

## 03/2023 - Present

Ongoing project for a utility cloud service.

Programming & managing a team for monthly business targets.

# **HOBBIES & PASSION**

# YOUTUBE:

I am passionate about sharing tech knowledge with people, so that only started my YouTube channel called "Nanum Coder.".

Exploring new APIs like OpenAI and Zenai and analyzing the use causes and finding solution for the application with integration